<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" ><generator uri="https://jekyllrb.com/" version="4.3.2">Jekyll</generator><link href="http://www.sdu-smile-lab.com/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/atom+xml" /><link href="http://www.sdu-smile-lab.com/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" /><updated>2025-11-02T14:38:09+00:00</updated><id>http://www.sdu-smile-lab.com/feed.xml</id><title type="html">SDU SMILE TEAM</title><subtitle>We are a research team from the Life-Cycle Engineering Unit, Department of Green Technology, University of Southern Denmark</subtitle><entry><title type="html">Global Lithium Supply Chain Faces Systemic Risks from Network Complexity and Geopolitical Tensions</title><link href="http://www.sdu-smile-lab.com/2025/10/15/Global-Lithium-Supply-Chain-Faces-Systemic-Risks-from-Network-Complexity-and-Geopolitical-Tensions.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Global Lithium Supply Chain Faces Systemic Risks from Network Complexity and Geopolitical Tensions" /><published>2025-10-15T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2025-11-02T14:36:09+00:00</updated><id>http://www.sdu-smile-lab.com/2025/10/15/Global%20Lithium%20Supply%20Chain%20Faces%20Systemic%20Risks%20from%20Network%20Complexity%20and%20Geopolitical%20Tensions</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://www.sdu-smile-lab.com/2025/10/15/Global-Lithium-Supply-Chain-Faces-Systemic-Risks-from-Network-Complexity-and-Geopolitical-Tensions.html"><![CDATA[<p>A groundbreaking study involving researchers from the RISE team at Peking University and SMILE Lab from SDU reveals the hidden vulnerabilities in the global lithium supply chain network, a critical component for achieving carbon neutrality goals. The research, published in <em>Environmental Science &amp; Technology</em>, demonstrates how highly interconnected supply chains exhibit a “robust yet fragile” paradox—resilient to random shocks but vulnerable to targeted disruptions.</p>

<h3 id="the-lithium-challenge">The Lithium Challenge</h3>
<p>Lithium is essential for electric vehicle batteries and the global energy transition. However, the geographical mismatch between production and consumption regions, combined with highly concentrated supply sources and complex global trade networks, exposes the supply chain to unprecedented risks—from trade restrictions and resource nationalism to natural disasters and geopolitical conflicts.</p>

<h3 id="innovative-methodology">Innovative Methodology</h3>
<p>The research breaks new ground by combining trade-linked material flow analysis with multi-layer network modeling, creating a comprehensive map of the global lithium supply chain across six life cycle stages: ore, basic chemicals, chemical derivatives, final products, use, and recycling. The team extended traditional static network metrics (degree centrality, closeness centrality, betweenness centrality, eigenvector centrality, PageRank, and Laplacian centrality) to multi-layer networks and adapted dynamic cascading failure models to directed, weighted multi-layer networks.</p>

<h3 id="key-findings">Key Findings</h3>

<h4 id="highly-interconnected-but-geographically-concentrated">Highly Interconnected but Geographically Concentrated</h4>
<p>In 2022, the lithium supply chain multi-layer network comprised <strong>865 nodes across 225 countries and 6 life cycle stages</strong>, with 14,362 intra-layer links (trade relationships) and 634 inter-layer links (production, processing, and consumption relationships).
Critical statistics include:</p>
<ul>
  <li><strong>45% of global lithium ore</strong>  (83 kt out of 183 kt) enters international trade, with Australia-to-China flows dominating at 79 kt</li>
  <li><strong>55% of basic lithium chemicals</strong> (119 kt out of 218 kt) are traded internationally with Chile, Argentina, Netherlands, and China as major exporters, while South Korea, Japan, and the US are primary importers</li>
  <li>China exports approximately <strong>30 kt of chemical derivatives and 10 kt of final products</strong> <br />
Australia, China, Chile, Japan, South Korea, the US, and the EU play pivotal roles, creating both efficiency and vulnerability.</li>
</ul>

<h4 id="robust-yet-fragile-network-characteristics">“Robust Yet Fragile” Network Characteristics</h4>

<p>The study identified different node types based on their roles in risk propagation:</p>
<ul>
  <li><strong>Risk Propagation Hubs</strong> (high degree centrality): Absorb random shocks but amplify targeted disruptions</li>
  <li><strong>Risk Amplifiers</strong> (high closeness centrality): Spread local disturbances via shortest paths</li>
  <li><strong>Risk Bridges</strong> (high betweenness centrality): Connect suppliers and consumers; disruption can fragment the network</li>
  <li><strong>Network Stabilizers</strong> (high Laplacian centrality): Maintain overall connectivity</li>
  <li><strong>Influential Risk Propagators</strong> (high eigenvector/PageRank): Highly connected with significant destructive potential</li>
</ul>

<h4 id="china-us-decoupling-scenarios">China-US Decoupling Scenarios</h4>
<p>The study simulated various degrees of China-US supply chain decoupling, revealing systemic implications:<br />
<strong>Direct Impact</strong>:China-US lithium trade represents only 3% of global trade volume, so even 100% decoupling would not improve the US’s systemic risk position.<br />
<strong>Indirect Impact</strong>:The cascading effects are substantial:</p>
<ul>
  <li>In <strong>100% decoupling</strong> scenarios:
    <ul>
      <li><strong>61 countries</strong> see increased dynamic criticality (<strong>7%</strong> of global total)</li>
      <li><strong>73 countries</strong> experience increased dynamic vulnerability (<strong>7%</strong> increase)</li>
    </ul>
  </li>
  <li><strong>Germany, Poland, Hungary</strong> gain criticality at the expense of <strong>India, Vietnam, Australia</strong></li>
  <li><strong>Chile, India, Canada</strong> reduce vulnerability; <strong>Malawi, Mexico, Slovakia, Ukraine</strong> increase</li>
  <li>Most decoupling scenarios (<strong>50–100%</strong>) increase global systemic risk by ~<strong>5%</strong></li>
  <li>However, <strong>25% decoupling</strong> could reduce global dynamic vulnerability by <strong>8.26%</strong>, with only marginal increase in criticality → suggesting <strong>partial decoupling</strong> may balance efficiency and security</li>
</ul>

<h3 id="policy-implications">Policy Implications</h3>
<p>The research calls for global cooperation and collective efforts to avoid “zero-sum games” in securing lithium supply chains. As geopolitical tensions intensify and supply chains shift from global integration toward diversified confrontation, policymakers must move beyond simple diversification strategies toward strategic network topology optimization that balances efficiency and security.
Countries with high vulnerability need both internal optimization to improve self-sufficiency and external cooperation to integrate their domestic industries into regional and global supply chain networks, enhancing their competitive position and bargaining power.</p>

<p><img src="/images/20251015post_lithium.png" alt="20251015post_lithium" /></p>

<p><strong><a href="https://doi.org/10.1021/acs.est.4c10523">Read the full paper</a></strong> <br />
<em>Environmental Science &amp; Technology</em> is a leading international journal covering environmental science, technology, and policy research. Published biweekly by the <em>American Chemical Society</em> since 1967, it has an <strong>impact factor of 11.357 (2022–2023)</strong>.</p>]]></content><author><name></name></author><category term="Research," /><category term="Supply-chain," /><category term="Circular-economy," /><category term="Sustainability" /><summary type="html"><![CDATA[A groundbreaking study involving researchers from the RISE team at Peking University and SMILE Lab from SDU reveals the hidden vulnerabilities in the global lithium supply chain network, a critical component for achieving carbon neutrality goals. The research, published in Environmental Science &amp; Technology, demonstrates how highly interconnected supply chains exhibit a “robust yet fragile” paradox—resilient to random shocks but vulnerable to targeted disruptions.]]></summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="http://www.sdu-smile-lab.com/images/20251015post_lithium.png" /><media:content medium="image" url="http://www.sdu-smile-lab.com/images/20251015post_lithium.png" xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" /></entry><entry><title type="html">Hidden Environmental Cost of E-Mobility: New Study Reveals Massive Mining Waste from Electric Vehicle Production</title><link href="http://www.sdu-smile-lab.com/2025/10/15/Hidden-Environmental-Cost-of-E-Mobility-New-Study-Reveals-Massive-Mining-Waste-from-Electric-Vehicle-Production.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Hidden Environmental Cost of E-Mobility: New Study Reveals Massive Mining Waste from Electric Vehicle Production" /><published>2025-10-15T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2025-11-02T14:36:09+00:00</updated><id>http://www.sdu-smile-lab.com/2025/10/15/Hidden%20Environmental%20Cost%20of%20E-Mobility:%20New%20Study%20Reveals%20Massive%20Mining%20Waste%20from%20Electric%20Vehicle%20Production</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://www.sdu-smile-lab.com/2025/10/15/Hidden-Environmental-Cost-of-E-Mobility-New-Study-Reveals-Massive-Mining-Waste-from-Electric-Vehicle-Production.html"><![CDATA[<p>Associate Professor Wu Chen from the University of Southern Denmark (SDU) has co-authored a groundbreaking study revealing that the global shift to electric vehicles generates far more mining waste than previously understood. The research, recently accepted by <em>Nature Communications</em>, quantifies for the first time the complete “hidden flows”—mining waste including overburden, waste rock, and tailings—along China’s passenger car supply chain.</p>

<h3 id="alarming-findings">Alarming Findings</h3>
<p>Using China as a case study (the world’s largest NEV producer and consumer), the international research team led by Professor Kazuyo Matsubae (Tohoku University) and Professor Gang Liu (Peking University) found that:</p>
<ul>
  <li>A <strong>new energy vehicle (NEV)</strong> generates <strong>over 3 times</strong> the hidden flows of a conventional vehicle.</li>
  <li><strong>Hidden flows exceed eventual used resources by 35 times</strong>, with only <strong>3%</strong> of extracted materials entering the car sector.</li>
  <li><strong>1,163 million tons</strong> of materials were extracted to produce China’s passenger cars in <strong>2019</strong>, generating <strong>1,106 Mt</strong> of mining waste.</li>
  <li><strong>48%</strong> of these hidden flows occur <strong>outside China</strong>, primarily in <strong>Chile, Australia, Peru, and South Africa</strong>.</li>
</ul>

<h3 id="innovative-methodology">Innovative Methodology</h3>
<p>The study developed a global mine-site-specific database covering <strong>1,784 mines</strong> across 11 metal minerals and created a life-cycle-based Total Material Requirement (TMR) framework. This high-resolution approach reveals that critical battery materials—lithium, cobalt, and nickel—though comprising only 0.4-9.5% of direct material flows, contribute 6-41% of hidden flows per vehicle.</p>

<h3 id="path-forward">Path Forward</h3>
<p>The research identifies concrete mitigation strategies:</p>
<ul>
  <li><strong>Recycling copper</strong> (which contributes <strong>37%</strong> of hidden flows) could reduce total waste by <strong>35%</strong>.</li>
  <li><strong>Switching from NMC/NCA batteries to LFP batteries</strong> could achieve <strong>3–12%</strong> reduction.</li>
  <li><strong>Clean energy transition</strong> in smelting and refining could reduce hidden flows by <strong>13–14%</strong>.</li>
</ul>

<p>“About half of these hidden flows occur abroad, revealing an unequal distribution of environmental burdens,” notes the research team. “Achieving a sustainable e-mobility transition requires coordinated international cooperation along the entire supply chain—from mining countries improving extraction practices to manufacturing countries adopting responsible sourcing and efficient product designs.”
The findings underscore the need to balance greenhouse gas reduction goals with broader environmental sustainability, ensuring that the transition to electric mobility doesn’t simply shift environmental problems from emissions to mining waste.</p>

<p><img src="/images/20251015post.png" alt="20251015post" /></p>

<p><strong>Paper status</strong>: Accepted by <em>Nature Communications</em> (in press)<br />
<em>Nature Communications</em> is a premier open-access multidisciplinary journal publishing high-quality research across all areas of the natural sciences.</p>]]></content><author><name></name></author><category term="Research," /><category term="Circular-economy," /><category term="Sustainability," /><category term="E-mobility" /><summary type="html"><![CDATA[Associate Professor Wu Chen from the University of Southern Denmark (SDU) has co-authored a groundbreaking study revealing that the global shift to electric vehicles generates far more mining waste than previously understood. The research, recently accepted by Nature Communications, quantifies for the first time the complete “hidden flows”—mining waste including overburden, waste rock, and tailings—along China’s passenger car supply chain.]]></summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="http://www.sdu-smile-lab.com/images/20251015post.png" /><media:content medium="image" url="http://www.sdu-smile-lab.com/images/20251015post.png" xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" /></entry><entry><title type="html">SDU Research Reveals Nordic Plastic Recycling Gap Despite Environmental Leadership</title><link href="http://www.sdu-smile-lab.com/2025/10/07/SDU-Research-Reveals-Nordic-Plastic-Recycling-Gap-Despite-Environmental-Leadership.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="SDU Research Reveals Nordic Plastic Recycling Gap Despite Environmental Leadership" /><published>2025-10-07T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2025-11-02T14:36:09+00:00</updated><id>http://www.sdu-smile-lab.com/2025/10/07/SDU%20Research%20Reveals%20Nordic%20Plastic%20Recycling%20Gap%20Despite%20Environmental%20Leadership</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://www.sdu-smile-lab.com/2025/10/07/SDU-Research-Reveals-Nordic-Plastic-Recycling-Gap-Despite-Environmental-Leadership.html"><![CDATA[<p>Despite their global reputation for environmental leadership, Nordic countries face significant challenges in plastic waste management, according to a new study co-led by Associate Professor Wu Chen from the University of Southern Denmark (SDU). The research, published in <em>ACS Sustainable Resource Management</em>, provides the first comprehensive, polymer-level analysis of plastic flows across all five Nordic nations.</p>

<h3 id="surprising-findings">Surprising Findings</h3>
<p>The study reveals a stark contrast between the Nordic region’s environmental ambitions and its plastic recycling reality. While these countries have among the world’s most comprehensive policy frameworks for sustainability, less than <strong>6% of plastic waste is actually recycled</strong>, with over 70% being incinerated.</p>

<h3 id="key-insights">Key Insights</h3>
<p>Using dynamic material flow analysis, the team tracked 14 polymer groups across Denmark, Finland, Norway, Sweden, and Iceland from 1978 to 2020, analyzing over 5.4 million trade records:</p>
<ul>
  <li>Nordic countries have the <strong>world’s highest per capita plastic stocks</strong> at <strong>1,100 kg per person</strong> in 2020, reaching saturation levels.</li>
  <li><strong>Denmark and Norway</strong> lead in consumption with over <strong>200 kg per capita annually</strong>, far exceeding the European average of <strong>119.4 kg</strong>.</li>
  <li><strong>Imports dominate supply</strong>: All five countries import more plastic products than they produce domestically.</li>
  <li><strong>Packaging</strong> is the main culprit, accounting for <strong>one-third</strong> of all plastic waste.</li>
  <li>By <strong>2050</strong>, unrecycled plastic waste could reach <strong>4.5 million tons annually</strong> under business-as-usual scenarios.</li>
</ul>

<h3 id="the-path-forward">The Path Forward</h3>
<p>The research evaluated three recycling scenarios to 2050, revealing both opportunities and challenges:
<strong>Enhanced Mechanical Recycling (R1)</strong>: Could meet 27% of regional plastic demand but requires <strong>expanding current capacity 6.7 times</strong> by 2050.
<strong>Chemical Recycling without Pyrolysis (R2)</strong>: Could only satisfy 5% of demand, with potential limited by the region’s minimal production capacity for key polymers like PET and polyester fibers.
<strong>Chemical Recycling with Steam Cracking (R3)</strong>: Offers the greatest potential at 22% of regional demand, but would reduce unrecycled waste to just 21% of BAU levels. However, current pilot capacity of 16,000 tons/year is far below requirements.</p>

<h2 id="implications">Implications</h2>
<p>The study highlights that international cooperation is essential for Nordic countries to achieve their circular economy goals, particularly for chemical recycling where local industrial capacity is limited. Exporting collected plastic waste to countries with established facilities (such as Germany) may be necessary in the short term, while domestic capacity is developed.
“As one of the world’s most developed and environmentally conscious regions, the Nordic experience provides critical insights for other regions working to improve plastic waste management,” notes the research team.
The findings were supported by multiple funding sources including the EU TREASoURcE project, THRU and Climate-Compatible Packaging initiatives, and China’s National Natural Science Foundation.</p>

<p><img src="/images/20251007post.png" alt="20251007post" /></p>

<p><strong><a href="https://doi.org/10.1021/acssusresmgt.5c00143">Read the full paper</a></strong> <br />
<em>ACS Sustainable Resource Management</em> is an interdisciplinary journal publishing original research on the sustainable management of natural and waste resources, emphasizing systems thinking and planetary boundaries.</p>]]></content><author><name></name></author><category term="Research," /><category term="Circular-economy," /><category term="Sustainability" /><summary type="html"><![CDATA[Despite their global reputation for environmental leadership, Nordic countries face significant challenges in plastic waste management, according to a new study co-led by Associate Professor Wu Chen from the University of Southern Denmark (SDU). The research, published in ACS Sustainable Resource Management, provides the first comprehensive, polymer-level analysis of plastic flows across all five Nordic nations.]]></summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="http://www.sdu-smile-lab.com/images/20251007post.png" /><media:content medium="image" url="http://www.sdu-smile-lab.com/images/20251007post.png" xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" /></entry><entry><title type="html">SMILE Team Develop High-Resolution Global Dataset for Material Stocks</title><link href="http://www.sdu-smile-lab.com/2025/09/26/SMILE-Team-Develop-High-Resolution-Global-Dataset-for-Material-Stocks.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="SMILE Team Develop High-Resolution Global Dataset for Material Stocks" /><published>2025-09-26T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2025-11-02T14:36:09+00:00</updated><id>http://www.sdu-smile-lab.com/2025/09/26/SMILE%20Team%20Develop%20High-Resolution%20Global%20Dataset%20for%20Material%20Stocks</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://www.sdu-smile-lab.com/2025/09/26/SMILE-Team-Develop-High-Resolution-Global-Dataset-for-Material-Stocks.html"><![CDATA[<p>SMILE LAB has led the development of a groundbreaking global dataset that maps anthropogenic material stocks at unprecedented resolution. The research, published in <em>Scientific Data (Nature)</em>, provides the first comprehensive view of steel, aluminum, and cement stocks worldwide at a 500×500-meter grid resolution from 2000 to 2019.</p>

<h3 id="a-new-window-into-urban-material-accumulation">A New Window into Urban Material Accumulation</h3>
<p>The SDU team, including Associate Professor Wu Chen, Dr. Kun Sun, from the Department of Green Technology, collaborated with Professor Bailang Yu (East China Normal University) and Professor Gang Liu (Peking University) to create this high-resolution dataset. The work integrates reconciled nighttime light imagery with national material stock data, overcoming critical limitations in previous satellite-based approaches.
“Traditional approaches faced a trade-off between research scope and spatial resolution,” explains the research team. “Our dataset bridges this gap by combining top-down material flow analysis with advanced nighttime light data processing.”</p>

<h3 id="key-innovation">Key Innovation</h3>
<p>The dataset addresses two major challenges in previous global material stock maps:</p>
<ul>
  <li><strong>Enhanced resolution</strong>: Improves from 1km to 500m grid resolution, revealing finer spatial details within cities.</li>
  <li><strong>Improved accuracy</strong>: Mitigates saturation and blooming effects in nighttime light data that compromised earlier estimates. <br />
The methodology employs country-specific regression models that establish relationships between average material stocks and light intensity per unit area, accounting for distinct developmental patterns across 119 nations with known stock data.</li>
</ul>

<h3 id="global-implications">Global Implications</h3>
<p>The comprehensive dataset comprises <strong>60 TIFF files</strong> documenting <strong>three key construction materials</strong> over <strong>two decades</strong>. Validation studies demonstrate over 80% of city-level estimates fall within -20% to 40% of literature-reported values, confirming reasonable consistency despite geographic variations.
The research reveals:<br /></p>
<ul>
  <li>Global anthropogenic stocks continue to <strong>accumulate</strong>, with significant <strong>spatial heterogeneity</strong> between and within urban areas.</li>
  <li>Urban core areas show higher stock densities previously obscured by satellite data limitations.</li>
  <li>Distribution patterns highlight disparities in material accumulation across different development stages.</li>
</ul>

<h3 id="applications-for-sustainability">Applications for Sustainability</h3>
<p>This spatially explicit dataset serves as an essential resource for:</p>
<ul>
  <li><strong>Urban mining</strong>: Identifying recyclable material reservoirs for circular economy strategies.</li>
  <li><strong>Climate action</strong>: Carbon accounting and decarbonization planning through embodied emissions assessment.</li>
  <li><strong>Urban planning</strong>: Supporting strategic infrastructure development and waste management policies.</li>
  <li><strong>Policy development</strong>: Enabling sub-city level analysis crucial for localized sustainability initiatives.</li>
</ul>

<p>The dataset is supported by the Independent Research Fund Denmark (iBuildGreen project) and China’s National Natural Science Foundation, highlighting strong international collaboration in addressing global resource challenges.</p>

<p><img src="/images/20250615post.png" alt="20250615post" /></p>

<p><strong><a href="https://doi.org/10.6084/m9.figshare.19959362.v3">Access the dataset</a></strong> <br />
<strong><a href="https://doi.org/10.1038/s41597-025-05618-0">Read the full paper</a></strong> <br />
<em>Scientific Data</em> is a peer-reviewed, open-access journal for descriptions of datasets published by <em>Nature Portfolio</em>. The dataset will be maintained and updated every 3-5 years to ensure continued relevance for global sustainability research.</p>]]></content><author><name></name></author><category term="Research," /><category term="Circular-economy," /><category term="Urban-sustainability" /><summary type="html"><![CDATA[SMILE LAB has led the development of a groundbreaking global dataset that maps anthropogenic material stocks at unprecedented resolution. The research, published in Scientific Data (Nature), provides the first comprehensive view of steel, aluminum, and cement stocks worldwide at a 500×500-meter grid resolution from 2000 to 2019.]]></summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="http://www.sdu-smile-lab.com/images/20250615post.png" /><media:content medium="image" url="http://www.sdu-smile-lab.com/images/20250615post.png" xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" /></entry><entry><title type="html">SMILE Team Contributes to Landmark Study on Global Sand and Gravel Resources</title><link href="http://www.sdu-smile-lab.com/2025/06/15/SMILE-Team-Contributes-to-Landmark-Study-on-Global-Sand-and-Gravel-Resources.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="SMILE Team Contributes to Landmark Study on Global Sand and Gravel Resources" /><published>2025-06-15T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2025-11-02T14:36:09+00:00</updated><id>http://www.sdu-smile-lab.com/2025/06/15/SMILE%20Team%20Contributes%20to%20Landmark%20Study%20on%20Global%20Sand%20and%20Gravel%20Resources</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://www.sdu-smile-lab.com/2025/06/15/SMILE-Team-Contributes-to-Landmark-Study-on-Global-Sand-and-Gravel-Resources.html"><![CDATA[<p>SMILE Team has co-authored a groundbreaking study that reveals critical insights into the global sand and gravel crisis. The research, published in <em>Resources, Conservation and Recycling</em>, tracks five decades of sand and gravel stocks and flows across 184 countries.</p>

<h3 id="key-findings">Key Findings</h3>
<p>The study challenges common assumptions about construction materials, revealing that <strong>global gravel extraction is twice that of sand</strong> (22.1 billion tons versus 10.3 billion tons in 2019), yet <strong>sand dominates international trade</strong> at 1.9 times the volume of gravel. This discrepancy highlights the greater trade dependency and supply vulnerability for sand resources</p>

<h3 id="why-it-matters">Why It Matters</h3>
<p>While sand and gravel are often studied together, this research demonstrates the importance of distinguishing between them. Sand (particles &lt;2mm) and gravel (larger particles) serve different functions in construction, have distinct life cycle behaviors, and face different supply challenges. The study found that:</p>
<ul>
  <li><strong>Asia accounts for 54.6%</strong> of global sand stocks, driven by rapid urbanization</li>
  <li><strong>Singapore</strong> remains the world’s largest sand importer, making it particularly vulnerable to trade disruptions</li>
  <li>Per capita sand consumption continues to rise globally, while gravel stocks in industrialized regions show signs of saturation</li>
</ul>

<h3 id="implications-for-sustainability">Implications for Sustainability</h3>
<p>The findings underscore the urgent need for improved recycling technologies, policy support for artificial aggregates, and better resource management strategies. As developing regions in Africa, South America, and Southeast Asia continue urbanizing, demand for these materials will surge, intensifying the risk of resource depletion and environmental damage.
The research was supported by multiple funding sources, including the Independent Research Fund Denmark (iBuildGreen project), highlighting the international collaboration essential to addressing global resource challenges.</p>

<p><img src="/images/20250615post2.png" alt="20250615post2" /></p>

<hr />

<p><strong><a href="https://doi.org/10.1016/j.resonrec.2025.108460">Read the full paper</a></strong> <br />
<em>Resources, Conservation and Recycling (Impact Factor: 11.2)</em> is a leading international journal in sustainable resource management, published by <em>Elsevier</em>.</p>]]></content><author><name></name></author><category term="Research," /><category term="Circular-economy," /><category term="Built-environment" /><summary type="html"><![CDATA[SMILE Team has co-authored a groundbreaking study that reveals critical insights into the global sand and gravel crisis. The research, published in Resources, Conservation and Recycling, tracks five decades of sand and gravel stocks and flows across 184 countries.]]></summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="http://www.sdu-smile-lab.com/images/20250615post2.png" /><media:content medium="image" url="http://www.sdu-smile-lab.com/images/20250615post2.png" xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" /></entry><entry><title type="html">SDU Researchers Collaborate with Industry Partners Circue and Rambøll</title><link href="http://www.sdu-smile-lab.com/2025/05/08/quival-first-industry.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="SDU Researchers Collaborate with Industry Partners Circue and Rambøll" /><published>2025-05-08T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2025-11-02T14:36:09+00:00</updated><id>http://www.sdu-smile-lab.com/2025/05/08/quival-first-industry</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://www.sdu-smile-lab.com/2025/05/08/quival-first-industry.html"><![CDATA[<p>On May 8th, the research team from the University of Southern Denmark (SDU)—Morten Birkved, Wu Chen, Xinyi Jiang, Antonia Klipp, and Zinan Lin—held their first in-person meeting with industry partners Lene Brix from Circue and Pernille Krohn Ohms from Rambøll in Copenhagen.</p>

<p>The meeting opened with an introduction to the QuiVal project, outlining its goals and relevance in promoting sustainable practices within the built environment. Three PhD candidates then took the stage to showcase their research plans, presenting collaborative proposals aimed at enhancing the project. They also discussed the challenges they have encountered in their research and the types of partnerships they seek from the industry. Their insights emphasized the importance of industry collaboration in advancing circular economy principles.</p>

<p>Lene provided an overview of Circue’s mission, which focuses on creating a digital platform that ensures the quality and value of building stock through data-driven analysis and insights. This platform helps building owners optimize their assets and make informed decisions about maintenance and improvements. Pernille shared valuable insights into Rambøll’s experiences, highlighting an increasing client interest in reusing materials and components. She noted that there is significant room for improvement in business models and the need to enhance stakeholder awareness regarding sustainability demands.</p>

<p>The meeting established a strong foundation for what is expected to be a productive collaboration. The discussions enhanced the understanding of each party’s objectives and strengths, setting the stage for effective cooperation. We look forward to three years of shared learning and impactful results.</p>

<p><img src="/images/Image.jpg" alt="Industry Partners" /></p>]]></content><author><name></name></author><category term="QuiVal," /><category term="Built-Environment," /><category term="Industry" /><summary type="html"><![CDATA[On May 8th, the research team from the University of Southern Denmark (SDU)—Morten Birkved, Wu Chen, Xinyi Jiang, Antonia Klipp, and Zinan Lin—held their first in-person meeting with industry partners Lene Brix from Circue and Pernille Krohn Ohms from Rambøll in Copenhagen.]]></summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="http://www.sdu-smile-lab.com/images/Image.jpg" /><media:content medium="image" url="http://www.sdu-smile-lab.com/images/Image.jpg" xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" /></entry><entry><title type="html">QuiVal Doctoral Network Kicks Off at TU Delft</title><link href="http://www.sdu-smile-lab.com/2025/03/07/quiVal-kickoff.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="QuiVal Doctoral Network Kicks Off at TU Delft" /><published>2025-03-07T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2025-11-02T14:36:09+00:00</updated><id>http://www.sdu-smile-lab.com/2025/03/07/quiVal-kickoff</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://www.sdu-smile-lab.com/2025/03/07/quiVal-kickoff.html"><![CDATA[<p>The QuiVal MSCA Doctoral Network officially launched with a workshop hosted by TU Delft, bringing together 13 PhD candidates and academic staff from partner universities across Europe.</p>

<p>The event introduced the program’s interdisciplinary approach to circular economy in real estate, with sessions led by faculty and industry partners. PhD candidates also presented their research topics and began planning their collaborative work for the coming years.</p>

<p>We look forward to the exciting research and innovation ahead.</p>

<p><img src="/images/QuiValKickoff.jpg" alt="QuiVal Kickoff" /></p>]]></content><author><name></name></author><category term="QuiVal," /><category term="Built-Environment" /><summary type="html"><![CDATA[The QuiVal MSCA Doctoral Network officially launched with a workshop hosted by TU Delft, bringing together 13 PhD candidates and academic staff from partner universities across Europe.]]></summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="http://www.sdu-smile-lab.com/images/QuiValKickoff.jpg" /><media:content medium="image" url="http://www.sdu-smile-lab.com/images/QuiValKickoff.jpg" xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" /></entry></feed>