<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" ><generator uri="https://jekyllrb.com/" version="4.3.2">Jekyll</generator><link href="http://www.sdu-smile-lab.com/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/atom+xml" /><link href="http://www.sdu-smile-lab.com/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" /><updated>2025-11-01T09:43:44+00:00</updated><id>http://www.sdu-smile-lab.com/feed.xml</id><title type="html">SDU SMILE LAB</title><subtitle>We are a research team from the Life-Cycle Engineering Unit, Department of Green Technology, University of Southern Denmark</subtitle><entry><title type="html">Hidden Environmental Cost of E-Mobility: New Study Reveals Massive Mining Waste from Electric Vehicle Production</title><link href="http://www.sdu-smile-lab.com/2025/10/15/Hidden-Environmental-Cost-of-E-Mobility-New-Study-Reveals-Massive-Mining-Waste-from-Electric-Vehicle-Production.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Hidden Environmental Cost of E-Mobility: New Study Reveals Massive Mining Waste from Electric Vehicle Production" /><published>2025-10-15T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2025-11-01T09:40:23+00:00</updated><id>http://www.sdu-smile-lab.com/2025/10/15/Hidden%20Environmental%20Cost%20of%20E-Mobility:%20New%20Study%20Reveals%20Massive%20Mining%20Waste%20from%20Electric%20Vehicle%20Production</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://www.sdu-smile-lab.com/2025/10/15/Hidden-Environmental-Cost-of-E-Mobility-New-Study-Reveals-Massive-Mining-Waste-from-Electric-Vehicle-Production.html"><![CDATA[<p>Associate Professor Wu Chen from the University of Southern Denmark (SDU) has co-authored a groundbreaking study revealing that the global shift to electric vehicles generates far more mining waste than previously understood. The research, recently accepted by <em>Nature Communications</em>, quantifies for the first time the complete “hidden flows”—mining waste including overburden, waste rock, and tailings—along China’s passenger car supply chain.</p>

<h2 id="alarming-findings">Alarming Findings</h2>
<p>Using <strong>China</strong> as a case study (the world’s largest NEV producer and consumer), the international research team led by <strong>Professor Kazuyo Matsubae</strong> (Tohoku University) and <strong>Professor Gang Liu</strong> (Peking University) found:</p>

<ul>
  <li>A <strong>new energy vehicle (NEV)</strong> generates <strong>over 3 times</strong> the hidden flows of a conventional vehicle.</li>
  <li><strong>Hidden flows exceed eventual used resources by 35 times</strong>, with only <strong>3%</strong> of extracted materials entering the car sector.</li>
  <li><strong>1,163 million tons</strong> of materials were extracted to produce China’s passenger cars in <strong>2019</strong>, generating <strong>1,106 Mt</strong> of mining waste.</li>
  <li><strong>48%</strong> of these hidden flows occur <strong>outside China</strong>, primarily in <strong>Chile, Australia, Peru, and South Africa</strong>.</li>
</ul>

<h2 id="innovative-methodology">Innovative Methodology</h2>

<p>The study developed a <strong>global mine-site-specific database</strong> covering <strong>1,784 mines</strong> across <strong>11 metal minerals</strong>, and created a <strong>life-cycle-based Total Material Requirement (TMR) framework</strong>.</p>

<p>This high-resolution approach reveals:</p>

<ul>
  <li>Critical battery materials—<strong>lithium, cobalt, and nickel</strong>—though comprising only <strong>0.4–9.5%</strong> of direct material flows, contribute <strong>6–41%</strong> of hidden flows per vehicle.</li>
</ul>

<h2 id="path-forward">Path Forward</h2>

<p>The research identifies <strong>concrete mitigation strategies</strong>:</p>

<ul>
  <li><strong>Recycling copper</strong> (which contributes <strong>37%</strong> of hidden flows) could reduce total waste by <strong>35%</strong>.</li>
  <li><strong>Switching from NMC/NCA batteries to LFP batteries</strong> could achieve <strong>3–12%</strong> reduction.</li>
  <li><strong>Clean energy transition</strong> in smelting and refining could reduce hidden flows by <strong>13–14%</strong>.</li>
</ul>

<blockquote>
  <p>“About half of these hidden flows occur abroad, revealing an unequal distribution of environmental burdens,” notes the research team.<br />
“Achieving a sustainable e-mobility transition requires coordinated international cooperation along the entire supply chain—from mining countries improving extraction practices to manufacturing countries adopting responsible sourcing and efficient product designs.”</p>
</blockquote>

<h2 id="conclusion">Conclusion</h2>

<p>The findings underscore the need to <strong>balance greenhouse gas reduction goals with broader environmental sustainability</strong>, ensuring that the transition to electric mobility doesn’t simply <strong>shift environmental problems from emissions to mining waste</strong>.</p>

<p><strong>Paper status</strong>: Accepted by <em>Nature Communications</em> (in press)
<strong>Nature Communications</strong> is a premier open-access multidisciplinary journal publishing high-quality research across all areas of the natural sciences.</p>]]></content><author><name></name></author><category term="Research," /><category term="Circular-economy," /><category term="Sustainability," /><category term="E-mobility" /><summary type="html"><![CDATA[Associate Professor Wu Chen from the University of Southern Denmark (SDU) has co-authored a groundbreaking study revealing that the global shift to electric vehicles generates far more mining waste than previously understood. The research, recently accepted by Nature Communications, quantifies for the first time the complete “hidden flows”—mining waste including overburden, waste rock, and tailings—along China’s passenger car supply chain.]]></summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="http://www.sdu-smile-lab.com/images/20251015post.png" /><media:content medium="image" url="http://www.sdu-smile-lab.com/images/20251015post.png" xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" /></entry><entry><title type="html">SDU Researchers Engage with QuiVal Partners Circue and Rambøll</title><link href="http://www.sdu-smile-lab.com/2025/05/08/quival-first-industry.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="SDU Researchers Engage with QuiVal Partners Circue and Rambøll" /><published>2025-05-08T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2025-11-01T09:40:23+00:00</updated><id>http://www.sdu-smile-lab.com/2025/05/08/quival-first-industry</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://www.sdu-smile-lab.com/2025/05/08/quival-first-industry.html"><![CDATA[<p>On May 8th, the research team from the University of Southern Denmark (SDU)—Morten Birkved, Wu Chen, Xinyi Jiang, Antonia Klipp, and Zinan Lin—held their first in-person meeting with industry partners Lene Brix from Circue and Pernille Krohn Ohms from Rambøll in Copenhagen.</p>

<p>The meeting opened with an introduction to the QuiVal project, outlining its goals and relevance in promoting sustainable practices within the built environment. Three PhD candidates then took the stage to showcase their research plans, presenting collaborative proposals aimed at enhancing the project. They also discussed the challenges they have encountered in their research and the types of partnerships they seek from the industry. Their insights emphasized the importance of industry collaboration in advancing circular economy principles.</p>

<p>Lene provided an overview of Circue’s mission, which focuses on creating a digital platform that ensures the quality and value of building stock through data-driven analysis and insights. This platform helps building owners optimize their assets and make informed decisions about maintenance and improvements. Pernille shared valuable insights into Rambøll’s experiences, highlighting an increasing client interest in reusing materials and components. She noted that there is significant room for improvement in business models and the need to enhance stakeholder awareness regarding sustainability demands.</p>

<p>The meeting established a strong foundation for what is expected to be a productive collaboration. The discussions enhanced the understanding of each party’s objectives and strengths, setting the stage for effective cooperation. We look forward to three years of shared learning and impactful results.</p>]]></content><author><name></name></author><category term="QuiVal," /><category term="Built-Environment," /><category term="Industry" /><summary type="html"><![CDATA[On May 8th, the research team from the University of Southern Denmark (SDU)—Morten Birkved, Wu Chen, Xinyi Jiang, Antonia Klipp, and Zinan Lin—held their first in-person meeting with industry partners Lene Brix from Circue and Pernille Krohn Ohms from Rambøll in Copenhagen.]]></summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="http://www.sdu-smile-lab.com/images/Image.jpg" /><media:content medium="image" url="http://www.sdu-smile-lab.com/images/Image.jpg" xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" /></entry><entry><title type="html">QuiVal Doctoral Network Kicks Off at TU Delft</title><link href="http://www.sdu-smile-lab.com/2025/03/07/quiVal-kickoff.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="QuiVal Doctoral Network Kicks Off at TU Delft" /><published>2025-03-07T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2025-11-01T09:40:23+00:00</updated><id>http://www.sdu-smile-lab.com/2025/03/07/quiVal-kickoff</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://www.sdu-smile-lab.com/2025/03/07/quiVal-kickoff.html"><![CDATA[<p>The QuiVal MSCA Doctoral Network officially launched with a workshop hosted by TU Delft, bringing together 13 PhD candidates and academic staff from partner universities across Europe.</p>

<p>The event introduced the program’s interdisciplinary approach to circular economy in real estate, with sessions led by faculty and industry partners. PhD candidates also presented their research topics and began planning their collaborative work for the coming years.</p>

<p>We look forward to the exciting research and innovation ahead.</p>]]></content><author><name></name></author><category term="QuiVal," /><category term="Built-Environment" /><summary type="html"><![CDATA[The QuiVal MSCA Doctoral Network officially launched with a workshop hosted by TU Delft, bringing together 13 PhD candidates and academic staff from partner universities across Europe.]]></summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="http://www.sdu-smile-lab.com/images/QuiVal%20Kickoff.jpg" /><media:content medium="image" url="http://www.sdu-smile-lab.com/images/QuiVal%20Kickoff.jpg" xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" /></entry></feed>