<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" ><generator uri="https://jekyllrb.com/" version="4.3.2">Jekyll</generator><link href="https://sdu-smilelab.com/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/atom+xml" /><link href="https://sdu-smilelab.com/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" /><updated>2025-10-03T18:45:41+00:00</updated><id>https://sdu-smilelab.com/feed.xml</id><title type="html">SDU SMILE Group</title><subtitle>We are a research team from the Life-Cycle Engineering Unit, Department of Green Technology, University of Southern Denmark</subtitle><entry><title type="html">Kickstarting Collaboration-SDU Researchers Present to Circue and Rambøll</title><link href="https://sdu-smilelab.com/2025/05/08/quival-first-industry.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Kickstarting Collaboration-SDU Researchers Present to Circue and Rambøll" /><published>2025-05-08T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2025-10-03T18:40:29+00:00</updated><id>https://sdu-smilelab.com/2025/05/08/quival-first-industry</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://sdu-smilelab.com/2025/05/08/quival-first-industry.html"><![CDATA[<p>On May 8th, the research team from the University of Southern Denmark (SDU)—Morten Birkved, Wu Chen, Xinyi Jiang, Antonia Klipp, and Zinan Lin—held their first in-person meeting with industry partners Lene Brix from Circue and Pernille Krohn Ohms from Rambøll in Copenhagen.</p>

<p>The meeting opened with an introduction to the QuiVal project, outlining its goals and relevance in promoting sustainable practices within the built environment. Three PhD candidates then took the stage to showcase their research plans, presenting collaborative proposals aimed at enhancing the project. They also discussed the challenges they have encountered in their research and the types of partnerships they seek from the industry. Their insights emphasized the importance of industry collaboration in advancing circular economy principles.</p>

<p>Lene provided an overview of Circue’s mission, which focuses on creating a digital platform that ensures the quality and value of building stock through data-driven analysis and insights. This platform helps building owners optimize their assets and make informed decisions about maintenance and improvements. Pernille shared valuable insights into Rambøll’s experiences, highlighting an increasing client interest in reusing materials and components. She noted that there is significant room for improvement in business models and the need to enhance stakeholder awareness regarding sustainability demands.</p>

<p>The meeting established a strong foundation for what is expected to be a productive collaboration. The discussions enhanced the understanding of each party’s objectives and strengths, setting the stage for effective cooperation. We look forward to three years of shared learning and impactful results.</p>]]></content><author><name></name></author><category term="QuiVal," /><category term="Built-Environment" /><summary type="html"><![CDATA[On May 8th, the research team from the University of Southern Denmark (SDU)—Morten Birkved, Wu Chen, Xinyi Jiang, Antonia Klipp, and Zinan Lin—held their first in-person meeting with industry partners Lene Brix from Circue and Pernille Krohn Ohms from Rambøll in Copenhagen.]]></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">QuiVal Doctoral Network Kicks Off at TU Delft</title><link href="https://sdu-smilelab.com/2025/03/07/quiVal-kickoff.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="QuiVal Doctoral Network Kicks Off at TU Delft" /><published>2025-03-07T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2025-10-03T18:40:29+00:00</updated><id>https://sdu-smilelab.com/2025/03/07/quiVal-kickoff</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://sdu-smilelab.com/2025/03/07/quiVal-kickoff.html"><![CDATA[<p>The QuiVal MSCA Doctoral Network officially launched with a workshop hosted by TU Delft, bringing together 13 PhD candidates and academic staff from partner universities across Europe.</p>

<p>The event introduced the program’s interdisciplinary approach to circular economy in real estate, with sessions led by faculty and industry partners. PhD candidates also presented their research topics and began planning their collaborative work for the coming years.</p>

<p>We look forward to the exciting research and innovation ahead.</p>

<p>!QuiVal Kickoff</p>]]></content><author><name></name></author><category term="QuiVal," /><category term="Built-Environment" /><summary type="html"><![CDATA[The QuiVal MSCA Doctoral Network officially launched with a workshop hosted by TU Delft, bringing together 13 PhD candidates and academic staff from partner universities across Europe.]]></summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="https://sdu-smilelab.com/images/QuiVal%20Kickoff.jpg" /><media:content medium="image" url="https://sdu-smilelab.com/images/QuiVal%20Kickoff.jpg" xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" /></entry></feed>